<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>OpenDataAlex's Blog</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="www.opendataalex.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>www.opendataalex.com/</id><updated>2020-10-20T10:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Introducing Tweakstreet</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/introducing-tweakstreet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-20T10:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-20T10:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-10-20:www.opendataalex.com/introducing-tweakstreet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introducing Tweakstreet&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've known me for any length of time, you know my love of and heavy use of open source.  Rarely though I'll
find tools that aren't pure open source that are quite worthwhile to have in the toolbox.  For a long time, my main
go-to data integration …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introducing Tweakstreet&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've known me for any length of time, you know my love of and heavy use of open source.  Rarely though I'll
find tools that aren't pure open source that are quite worthwhile to have in the toolbox.  For a long time, my main
go-to data integration tool has been &lt;a href="https://help.pentaho.com/Documentation/9.0/Products/Pentaho_Data_Integration"&gt;Pentaho's Data Integration&lt;/a&gt; 
(aka Kettle aka &lt;a href="https://incubator.apache.org/clutch/hop.html"&gt;Apache Hop&lt;/a&gt;).  Another long time member of the Kettle
community (@slawo) has been working for the past year on a new modern data integration tool called &lt;a href="https://tweakstreet.io/"&gt;Tweakstreet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using Tweakstreet exclusively for the past few months to really kick the tires and have to say it's an
awesome tool and coming along (and I would argue, surpassing) feature parity with many of the other big name data integration
tools including Kettle.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be adding some blog posts with some tips and tricks I've hit that may be helpful for others who want to start playing around with it.
Go ahead and check it out - there's a &lt;a href="https://tweakstreet.io/download"&gt;unlimited trial&lt;/a&gt; going on now and if you do go
for a license, they are quite reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Open Source backing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now another factor about Tweakstreet that I'll mention here is &lt;a href="https://twineworks.github.io/tweakflow/index.html"&gt;Tweakflow&lt;/a&gt;,
an open source embeddable scripting language for JVM and used in Tweakstreet.  This can be used in other tools and is pretty
powerful on its own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tutorials"></category><category term="Tweakstreet"></category><category term="data integration"></category></entry><entry><title>A Sad Day For Open Source</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/a-sad-day-for-open-source.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-28T18:23:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-28T18:23:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-10-28:www.opendataalex.com/a-sad-day-for-open-source.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is a sad day for open source.  I found out only a couple of hours ago that Red Hat, like
many other open source companies before it, decided to sell itself to a group that will likely
do what Oracle did to Sun Microsystems.  It's a damn shame.  The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is a sad day for open source.  I found out only a couple of hours ago that Red Hat, like
many other open source companies before it, decided to sell itself to a group that will likely
do what Oracle did to Sun Microsystems.  It's a damn shame.  The only way this will work is if
IBM is smart enough to leave Red Hat as is and just utilize it for integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine all my friends over there must be all kinds of livid/concerned.  Chin up and hope for
the best while preparing for the worst.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Open Source"></category></entry><entry><title>Setting Up New Blog - Pelican Edition</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/setting-up-new-blog-pelican-edition.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-27T11:16:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T11:16:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-10-27:www.opendataalex.com/setting-up-new-blog-pelican-edition.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been wanting to do this for a while now, and finally found the time/bit the bullet.  Wordpress, while awesome, 
just wasn't cutting it for me - especially since I had to pay quite a bit for hosting and the like.
For now, I'll use GitHub pages and go from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been wanting to do this for a while now, and finally found the time/bit the bullet.  Wordpress, while awesome, 
just wasn't cutting it for me - especially since I had to pay quite a bit for hosting and the like.
For now, I'll use GitHub pages and go from there.  I have also switched over to using Pelican.
My plan is to get all the old content re-posted into the new blog, which I don't think will be too 
much trouble.  Just have to find the time. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category></entry><entry><title>MySQL Case</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/mysql-case.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-04-11T10:35:23-04:00</published><updated>2009-04-11T10:35:23-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2009-04-11:www.opendataalex.com/mysql-case.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was in the midst of developing a system to track OTIF (On Time In Full)  deliveries to my employer's customers.  I 
wanted to be able to take the data and use it with a nice open source sparkline tool found &lt;a href="http://sparkline.org/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that though, I needed to be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was in the midst of developing a system to track OTIF (On Time In Full)  deliveries to my employer's customers.  I 
wanted to be able to take the data and use it with a nice open source sparkline tool found &lt;a href="http://sparkline.org/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that though, I needed to be able to convert the data into a binary setting - either we met the OTIF goal fot the 
delivery, or we didn't.  Luckily, I found out about &lt;a href="http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.0/en/case-statement.html"&gt;MySQL Reference - Case Statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I go over the case statement function, let's build a table in MySQL and populate it with some data.  The table 
will be similar to the table I used with the above problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table Name: otif_data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| ID  |   Customer ID  |  Quantity Ordered  |  Quantity Shipped  |  Date Due  |  Date Shipped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now that we have our table built, I'll let you go ahead and populate some data.  For illustrative purposes, I'll 
put a couple of rows here so you get the idea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;ID&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Customer ID&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;Quantity Ordered&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;Quantity Shipped&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Date Due&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Date Shipped&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alpha Pakages&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;10,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;9,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2008-04-20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2008-04-21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jingle Jangle's&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;20,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;20,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2008-04-21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2008-04-18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ying's Pottery Barn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;15,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;15,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2008-04-22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2008-04-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now for the real fun.  MySQL's case statement works just like an if statement in any programming language.  Let's
look at the code required to test for how many customers we have shipped orders to on time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Time Query&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SELECT SUM(CASE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update 10/28/2018:  I believe this was an incomplete tutorial I had in WordPress.  I leave it posted here because I will likely 
come back and clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="MySQL"></category></entry><entry><title>When Adding Plugins To Your Symfony Project</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/when-adding-plugins-to-your-symfony-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-09-16T20:09:26-04:00</published><updated>2008-09-16T20:09:26-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-09-16:www.opendataalex.com/when-adding-plugins-to-your-symfony-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had the roughest time getting this one going - so therefore I'm posting just in case anyone else gets stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I started adding user security to the training database I've been developing in Symfony 1.1.  One of the great 
things about a strong framework like Symfony is the ability …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had the roughest time getting this one going - so therefore I'm posting just in case anyone else gets stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I started adding user security to the training database I've been developing in Symfony 1.1.  One of the great 
things about a strong framework like Symfony is the ability to create/distribute plugins to increase the core 
framework's functionality.  A very popular plugin, that I decided to use for my project, is &lt;a href="http://www.symfony-project.org/plugins/sfGuardPlugin"&gt;sfGuardPlugin&lt;/a&gt;.  
This plugin handles security with groups and a bunch of other features that I haven't played with yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a real good instruction set for installation/configuration with the plugin.  However, one thing not mentioned in
 the instructions is the fact that you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to update your schema.xml file.  Otherwise, propel will throw this nice 
error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No package found for database "propel" in schema.xml.  The propel.packageObjectModel property requires the package 
attribute to be set for each database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you'll need to update your schema file from this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"&amp;gt;
    &lt;database name="propel" defaultIdMethod="native" noxsd="true"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"&amp;gt;
   &lt;database name="propel" defaultIdMethod="native" noxsd="true" **package="lib.model"**&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why is due to when a plugin has a schema of it's own.  Symfony/Propel will attempt to merge the plugin schema
with your application schema.  Your application schema though is not initially setup to handle this kind of merger.  
Adding that one variable should take care of that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit:  I originally had the change to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;package="model"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was incorrect and will result in your forms and models being stored in the primay folder for your symfony project - 
which will result in you wondering what the hell happened (as has been my problem for the last two days =S).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="symfony"></category><category term="WebDev"></category></entry><entry><title>Magento Update: Backend Fun/Frustration</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/magento-update-backend-funfrustration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-08-24T08:48:49-04:00</published><updated>2008-08-24T08:48:49-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-08-24:www.opendataalex.com/magento-update-backend-funfrustration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that there's been interest with Magento, I figured I would write up my experiences since the last time I 
published about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, Magento does a fairly good job about documenting the basics about the program.  As I found out last time, it
will take a bit of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that there's been interest with Magento, I figured I would write up my experiences since the last time I 
published about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, Magento does a fairly good job about documenting the basics about the program.  As I found out last time, it
will take a bit of digging to get into super-specific problems - mine just happened to be a host issue that had to be 
worked around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, to access the administration side of the system, you need to go to the root directory of where you placed 
Magento and add /admin to the end of the address.  In my case, I actually created a store folder to keep it separate 
from the rest of the website so the address would look similar to:  http://somesite.com/store/admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now during the installation process, you created an administrator account.  Using that will get you access to the 
backend - which happens to be a nice sales dashboard (one of the features that really sold me on Magento is the 
reporting capabilities build in, not sure if other OSS e-commerce solutions do something similar.  Feel free to post a 
comment and let me know what's up with the other solutions.  Heck, if you have a good review of any of them, send it to 
me too =p).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my big quips about Magento at this point is that even with my broadband connection, Magento seems to take it's 
time loading initially, which I sincerely hope they work on in future releases.  Also at first brush, it seems a bit 
complex to build addon modules for Magento, which I have also seen comments about elsewhere when reading reviews about 
php|architect\'s Magento guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do like how the menu is organized, with the ability to create promotions for a particular date range, newsletter 
creation, and the ability to create personalized themes for stores (haven't worked on creating one yet, but I do like 
that they give the option).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, I'll keep playing around with Magento (when I'm not delving into symfony =p) and see what else I can come up 
with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="Magento"></category></entry><entry><title>Symfony PHP Framework</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/symfony-php-framework.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-08-05T20:09:49-04:00</published><updated>2008-08-05T20:09:49-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-08-05:www.opendataalex.com/symfony-php-framework.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I've spent the better part of a week and a half/two weeks working on getting up to speed on Symfony, the PHP 
framework I finally settled down to using.  If you haven't heard about it, I strongly suggest you check it out.  It's a 
very user-friendly framework, with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I've spent the better part of a week and a half/two weeks working on getting up to speed on Symfony, the PHP 
framework I finally settled down to using.  If you haven't heard about it, I strongly suggest you check it out.  It's a 
very user-friendly framework, with the ability to build on the base code and extremely easy to get into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://symfony-project.com"&gt;Symfony Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some excellent documentation to read - including an open sourced copy of the printed manual, which is updated 
with the latest and greatest data about each version (currently running at 1.0, 1.1, and 1.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to start running through the Askeet tutorial - which is currently just for version 1.0, but stubborn as I am, 
I've been working with the latest version of 1.1, with the intent of moving to 1.2 when it becomes fully stable.  If you
are up to the challenge yourself, feel free to drop a line if you have any questions, or check out the &lt;a href="http://www.symfony-project.org/forum/"&gt;community forums&lt;/a&gt;
- you'll see me up there, mainly in the Askeet forum atm (DBA_Alex, just fyi =p ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have gotten up to day 11, which is where I'll be picking back up tomorrow.  I'm truly looking forward to when the 
project team finally updates the askeet tutorial for the other symfony versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, tonight I'm getting back to work on updating the blog's design to match the rest of the site - something I hope 
to complete before the week is out.  Once I finish that, I'll be pushing out a few tutorials that I've held onto which 
I've been polishing up - one on Pentaho report creation, and another on using the php sparkline program.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="Symfony"></category><category term="WebDev"></category></entry><entry><title>Firefox 3 World Record</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/firefox-3-world-record.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-07-06T20:47:14-04:00</published><updated>2008-07-06T20:47:14-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-07-06:www.opendataalex.com/firefox-3-world-record.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to make a quick post saying congrats to the Mozilla team for successfully hitting the world record for the 
most software downloads in a 24 hour period, as well as making the most kick-ass browsing experience I've ever had 
possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been using Firefox 3 since before Download …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to make a quick post saying congrats to the Mozilla team for successfully hitting the world record for the 
most software downloads in a 24 hour period, as well as making the most kick-ass browsing experience I've ever had 
possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been using Firefox 3 since before Download Day (btw - got your certificate for downloading FF3 yet?  If not, &lt;a href="http://www.spreadfirefox.com/en-US/worldrecord/certificate_form"&gt;clicky&lt;/a&gt;) 
and I must applaud the Mozilla group for all the hard work they put into the new version, and must say the plugin 
community really put the petal to the metal to ensure that most of the popular plugins worked with our new browser 
friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, I've kinda been out of the picture for a while due to my back/other things taking precident, but I'm still 
working on a few things coming up.  I hope I'll be able to finish at least one of them up this week for posting, we'll 
see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="Firefox"></category></entry><entry><title>PHP Frameworks</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/php-frameworks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-06-14T07:35:14-04:00</published><updated>2008-06-14T07:35:14-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-06-14:www.opendataalex.com/php-frameworks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So at work, I've started moving things into the 21st century tech-wise - implementing a software bug/feature tracking 
system and working on installing a subversion server (even if I am the only programmer there, it'll be a big help I 
think....).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something else I've been looking into for a while …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So at work, I've started moving things into the 21st century tech-wise - implementing a software bug/feature tracking 
system and working on installing a subversion server (even if I am the only programmer there, it'll be a big help I 
think....).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something else I've been looking into for a while is programming frameworks, specifically with PHP.  I've already found 
a Javascript framework that works well for my various projects (for those interested, it's &lt;a href="http://jquery.com/"&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt;).
I'm still looking around to find the just right PHP framework.  Recently I've been toying around with CakePHP, but if 
anyone reads this I'm wondering if you may have some suggestions - so there you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside before I wrap things up, the main site has been completely revamped, with more work coming soon to get the 
site truly polished up.  That polishing will also include true blog integration into the rest of the site, but more on 
that coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="WebDev"></category><category term="PHP"></category></entry><entry><title>Magento, GoDaddy Fun</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/magento-godaddy-fun.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-06-07T10:34:16-04:00</published><updated>2008-06-07T10:34:16-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-06-07:www.opendataalex.com/magento-godaddy-fun.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm starting to work with e-Commerce systems, and picked Magento because it has a very robust feature set (I still 
want to check out Zen Cart, for it also looks promising) .  I've about got my current customer's store up, just waiting 
on their host to setup the MySQL database …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm starting to work with e-Commerce systems, and picked Magento because it has a very robust feature set (I still 
want to check out Zen Cart, for it also looks promising) .  I've about got my current customer's store up, just waiting 
on their host to setup the MySQL database to finish the install.  Since I've got a bit of time to kill before that's 
complete, I figured I'd do a small writeup on how much fun GoDaddy brought to me lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so all you really need to download is the Magento version that you want to use.  Fortunately, GoDaddy finally 
caught up with the times and now provides PHP 5.2 with it's hosting packages.  Otherwise, you get to have fun with the 
&lt;a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/wiki/welcome_to_the_magento_user_s_guide/chapter_2"&gt;CGI last resort fix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I also found out that because GoDaddy hosts both PHP 4 AND PHP 5, developers have to change the file extensions from 
.php to .php5 (what fun, right?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, hunting around the Internet brought me a quick solution for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your Magento folder/setup, there should already be a .htaccess file.  Open that file up and add the following line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AddHandler x-httpd-php5 .php&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when you go to the Magento index page, you should see a 'No Input File Specified' error.  This is another easy fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not already have a php.ini file in your main folder, you need to create one.  This will only work if you have 
selected the option of using Hosting Connection 2.0 .  This will allow you to modify server settings for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to name my file 'php5.ini' for it to recognize.  I then added the following line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cgi.fix_pathinfo = 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoDaddy decided to behave at this point and allowed me to see the installation wizard. Do not despair if it doesn't work
- there's a few more things that can be done, just check out the official posting about this issue &lt;a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/wiki/groups/227/error/no_input_file_specified"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I only had one more error to pop up after this.  It came in the form of a nice long text box.  Apparently when I 
FTP'd the Magento software, one file didn't transfer over.  If this happens, just place the file where it belongs based 
off of the error message you may receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So once that's all done, you should also have Magento hosted on a GoDaddy account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I explore the features of Magento, I'll post my thoughts and ideas/tips up here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="Magento"></category><category term="WebDev"></category></entry><entry><title>Site Upgrade</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/site-upgrade.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-06-05T21:03:00-04:00</published><updated>2008-06-05T21:03:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-06-05:www.opendataalex.com/site-upgrade.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I'm back with a quick update - I'm close to getting ready to finish my site overhaul.  Not been able to work on 
the site or post in a while - it's been real busy around here, heh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also planning on getting those tutorials up soon as well.  If only …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I'm back with a quick update - I'm close to getting ready to finish my site overhaul.  Not been able to work on 
the site or post in a while - it's been real busy around here, heh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also planning on getting those tutorials up soon as well.  If only for more hours in the day =p&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category></entry><entry><title>Fighting IE CSS Bugs</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/fighting-ie-css-bugs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-05-10T15:05:29-04:00</published><updated>2008-05-10T15:05:29-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-05-10:www.opendataalex.com/fighting-ie-css-bugs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it's been another busy week.  I just spent the last hour fighting with Internet Explorer.  Fortunately we're back 
on speaking terms - for now anyway.  I'm working on a customer site that uses css floats.  Well and good with Firefox - 
looks very clean and stylish.  I'll post a link when …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it's been another busy week.  I just spent the last hour fighting with Internet Explorer.  Fortunately we're back 
on speaking terms - for now anyway.  I'm working on a customer site that uses css floats.  Well and good with Firefox - 
looks very clean and stylish.  I'll post a link when I'm finished with the site and have it up and running, but in the 
meantime check out the following link - also known as my Knight in CSS armor =p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.positioniseverything.net/explorer.html"&gt;How to force IE to behave&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a pretty nice site showing all the things that can go wrong when CSS and IE are in the same sandbox.  They seem to 
not like to share, and if you're not too careful they'll start trying to make each other eat dirt.....&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="front end"></category></entry><entry><title>Sparklines - the Cheetah of Line Charts</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/sparklines-the-cheetah-of-line-charts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-04-27T10:38:29-04:00</published><updated>2008-04-27T10:38:29-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-04-27:www.opendataalex.com/sparklines-the-cheetah-of-line-charts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So a large chunk of my daily job consists of finding better ways of viewing  and obtaining data.  Being the geeky 
individual I am, I do my best to push Open Source initiatives (as a real quick aside, anyone else had the extreme fun of
having to prove over and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So a large chunk of my daily job consists of finding better ways of viewing  and obtaining data.  Being the geeky 
individual I am, I do my best to push Open Source initiatives (as a real quick aside, anyone else had the extreme fun of
having to prove over and over again that Open Source can be high quality, enterprise-grade stuff?  I'm pretty sure that 
is the case in a lot of places, but it's good to hear the horror stories lol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So over the last two years I've come across many programs (&lt;a href="http://www.pentaho.com) and
[Open Flash Chart](http://teethgrinder.co.uk/open-flash-chart/) to name a couple..."&gt;Pentaho Business Intelligence&lt;/a&gt; and have recently come across a 
really neat little php app over at &lt;a href="http://sparkline.org)"&gt;Sparkline PHP Graphing Library&lt;/a&gt;:  an open source application
to build sparklines from databases/array data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are these sparklines anyway?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was first introduced to the concept of sparklines by reading Information Dashboard Design:  The Effective Visual 
Communication of Data by Stephen Few (&lt;a href="http://www.perceptualedge.com/"&gt;Stephen Few's company site&lt;/a&gt;.  If you're looking 
for a good overview on how to design information dashboards, I highly recommend picking it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sparklines were developed by Edward Tufte, who describes them as "data-intense, design-simple, word-sized graphics" 
(&lt;a href="http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0001OR&amp;amp;topic_id=1"&gt;here is&lt;/a&gt;  a post Tufte made about 
them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, they are a way to show a large chunk of data in a relatively small space.  Here's a few examples from 
sparkline.org:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/sparkline_examples.png\"&gt;&lt;img class=\"aligncenter size-medium wp-image-10\" title=\"sparkline_examples\" src=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/sparkline_examples.png\" alt=\"Large sparkline example\" width=\"200\" height=\"50\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/deficit_sparkline.png\"&gt;&lt;img class=\"aligncenter size-medium wp-image-11\" title=\"deficit_sparkline\" src=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/deficit_sparkline.png\" alt=\"bar style sparkline\" width=\"62\" height=\"16\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice there are two types - a line chart and a bar chart.  Both types can be embedded within a section of text to give 
quick, relevant data without breaking the stride of the writing.  As the first example also shows, you can also have 
sparklines be any size depending on what information you want to display.   I've been using them for On Time In Full 
calculations by customer - basically an overview page showing all customers on file with three sparklines beside them:&lt;br&gt;
one for On Time, In Full, and On Time In Full respectfully.  This way everyone (and I do mean everyone - I'm all about 
keeping data open to all those involved with the process) within the facility can see how well we are at shipping to our
 customers on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've gotten a tutorial about halfway finished on how to use the sparkline package with a mysql database (quick hint - 
 since OTIF is a hit/miss calculation, use a MySQL case statement to transform your data into a hit/miss total....).&lt;br&gt;
 Look for it soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT - Now here's some irony.  While looking through the WordPress widget repository, I came across this:  
 &lt;a href="http://widgets.wordpress.com/2006/08/14/sparkstats-widget/"&gt;Sparkstats Widget&lt;/a&gt;.  
 It even uses the Sparkline PHP Graphing Library.  Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Data Visualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Hacking My Windows Mobile PDA</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/hacking-my-windows-mobile-pda.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-04-22T22:01:43-04:00</published><updated>2008-04-22T22:01:43-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-04-22:www.opendataalex.com/hacking-my-windows-mobile-pda.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, the past weekend was fun - spent a good chuck of time hacking my PDA to have a better touch-based interface.&lt;br&gt;
This all started when I saw &lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/software/hack-attack/turn-your-windows-mobile-phone-into-an-iphone-269055.php"&gt;Turn Your Windows Mobile Phone Into an iPhone&lt;/a&gt;
over at Lifehacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the main reason why I wanted to do this was because …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, the past weekend was fun - spent a good chuck of time hacking my PDA to have a better touch-based interface.&lt;br&gt;
This all started when I saw &lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/software/hack-attack/turn-your-windows-mobile-phone-into-an-iphone-269055.php"&gt;Turn Your Windows Mobile Phone Into an iPhone&lt;/a&gt;
over at Lifehacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the main reason why I wanted to do this was because I never really liked my PDA - Windows Mobile is not a very user 
friendly interface.  I like things to have the capability of being very complex (i.e. being able to do all kinds of 
time saving features) but also ergonomic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the touch interface of the iPhone, I'm able to add that layer of ergonomics that has been lacking.  Yes yes, I 
know I was able to use all kinds of software before the iPhoneesque interface, but again, it's about the usability not 
just the functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, I got to digging around on the Internet and found a much better tutorial on how to perform such an interface 
conversion:  &lt;a href="http://hackaddict.blogspot.com/2007/06/tutorial-iphone-windows-mobile-skin.html"&gt;iPhone Windows Mobile Skin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following Jen's lovely guide, I was able to  get my  PDA using almost all of the software she suggested. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my PDA's install of S2U2 - it was once called Slide2Unlock.  Either way - it's a cool little app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/s2u2.jpg\"&gt; src=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/s2u2-199x300.jpg\" alt=\"What happens when my PDA goes to sleep\" width=\"199\" height=\"300\" /&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then of course, there is the main application, rlToday.  This app gives your PDA the basic iPhone-esque interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/main_screen.jpg\"&gt;&lt;img class=\"alignright size-medium wp-image-7\" title=\"main_screen\" src=\"http://www.bluefiredatasolutions.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/main_screen-220x300.jpg\" alt=\"rlToday on my PDA\" width=\"220\" height=\"300\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm now starting to play around with Touch Commander and UltimateLaunch - just google them, though they are not free, 
they get your PDA even more touch-interfacing to your apps.  I'll probably write up a review about them soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I do have some tutorials I am writing - but I've not finished either of them up.  Will get them up here 
soon though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category><category term="tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome To BlueFire</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/welcome-to-bluefire.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-04-10T22:32:46-04:00</published><updated>2008-04-10T22:32:46-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-04-10:www.opendataalex.com/welcome-to-bluefire.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, if anyone is reading this allow me to say, welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start off by explaining a bit about why I'm blogging here, what BlueFire is about, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Alex, and I am the founder of BlueFire Data Solutions.  There's still a lot of development going …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, if anyone is reading this allow me to say, welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start off by explaining a bit about why I'm blogging here, what BlueFire is about, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Alex, and I am the founder of BlueFire Data Solutions.  There's still a lot of development going on with the 
rest of the site (and seeing that I just got WordPress installed I've got work to do on my blog layout =p ) - even so, 
feel free to look around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been working with web-based database systems for about two years now, and wanted to continue further development 
in the field.  I started BlueFire to do just that.  While working with my current employer, I have developed the skills 
needed to move systems from paper-based over to fully electronic, validated systems.  These types of systems eliminate 
waste - time, resources, and movement. Instead of hunting down the necessary forms for that critical bit of information,
users are able to go to a centralized web-based system - available from any network connected device - and have access 
to that information in real time. Not only does efficiency increase, but think about if you're being audited - your 
company would be able to pull together information faster that ever before. Now, as for what else I'm planning for the 
blog.  I want to be able to provide gleams of information from my experiences on a daily basis as a database 
administrator.  I also want to provide tutorials for the various tools I use, especially where tutorials for some the 
of products I develop with are far and few between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, I'll end this posting for now, but look forward to a post later this week - maybe even a tutorial for Pentaho .....&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category></entry><entry><title>Setting Up New Blog</title><link href="www.opendataalex.com/setting-up-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-04-10T20:06:30-04:00</published><updated>2008-04-10T20:06:30-04:00</updated><author><name>Alex Meadows</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-04-10:www.opendataalex.com/setting-up-new-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog will cover quite a few facets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BlueFire Data Solutions: Goings on with my company - updates with the website, software development, etc. etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thoughts, Tips, and Nudges: Ideas that have run through my mind as I work on developing databases and software.&lt;br&gt;
    Tips and suggestions from the trenches, so …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog will cover quite a few facets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BlueFire Data Solutions: Goings on with my company - updates with the website, software development, etc. etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thoughts, Tips, and Nudges: Ideas that have run through my mind as I work on developing databases and software.&lt;br&gt;
    Tips and suggestions from the trenches, so to speak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutorials and Guides: (Hopefully) helpful tutorials and guides about various software that I use/am learning.&lt;br&gt;
    Some of the more recent software packages that will probably have a tutorial before too long are Magento, Symfony, MySQL, and GIMP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you have any suggestions, questions, coments, or concerns, please feel free to shoot me a line &lt;a href="alexmeadows@bluefiredatasolutions.com"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Archive"></category></entry></feed>